1982-0712 Bhoomi Devi Puja Talk, Birmingham, UK
19820712 - Bhúmí Déví púda, Birmingham, Anglie
that we should do of course the Puja of the Bhumi,
e bychom, samozøejmì, mìli udìlat púdu k Bhúmí Déví,
because She’s angry actually,
protoe se opravdu zlobí.
in this part of the country, and while the people who lived here
v této èásti zemì, zatímco lidé, kteøí zde ili,
have not understood the beauty that She has given them,
neporozumìli kráse, kterou jim dala,
and have tried to take to ugly
zkoušeli se dát na ošklivé
and very sinful methods  of invoking
a velmi høíšné zpùsoby probouzení
the satanic and negative forces.
satanskıch a negativních sil.
And this has made Her very angry,
A to Ji velmi rozhnìvalo.
I felt it the other day when we went out.
Cítila jsem to, kdy jsme šli poslednì ven.
And it is done through the ignorance of the people, no doubt,
A stalo se to díky nevìdomosti lidí, bezpochyby,
but still, some of them, even knowingly, are
ale nìkteøí stále, dokonce vìdomì,
indulging into things like these.
holdují takovım vìcem.
Is a very serious thing,
To je velmi váná vìc,
because you are inviting,
protoe zvete,
inviting the satanic forces to work out your destruction.
zvete satanské síly, aby vás znièily.
These forces are never your friends, they’re destructive,
Tyto síly nikdy nejsou vaši pøátelé, jsou nièivé,
they can never be your friends,
a nikdy nemohou bıt vaši pøátelé.
because you came out of the construction of God,
Protoe jste vzešli z tvoøení Boha
and they are the destructions, and they can never be your friends.
a ony jsou nièením, nemohou bıt nikdy vaši pøátelé.
So the nature has to be annoyed about it ,
Take pøíroda tím musí bıt nazlobená
and they think that this country doesn’t deserve a puja.
a myslí si, e si tato zemì púdu nezaslouí.
It is their own decision about it,
Je to jejich vlastní rozhodnutí.
that they are suggesting that this country doesn’t deserve…
Navrhují, e si to tato zemì nezaslouí.
But I am thinking I don’t know what this country has done,
Moná se domnívají, e nevím, èeho se tento kraj dopustil,
this part of the country and that what I should do about them.
tato èást zemì a co bych jim mìla udìlat.
To punish someone is very easy,
Potrestat nìkoho je velmi snadné.
and to get angry is even easier.
A rozzlobit se je ještì snadnìjší.
But to have poise, and understanding, and compassion, is difficult.
Ale mít rovnováhu a porozumìní a soucit je obtíné.
The patience of a mother they cannot have,
Trpìlivost Matky oni mít nemohou,
it’s alright, I can understand them –
to je v poøádku, já je chápu -
but they have to obey.
ale musí poslechnout.
Something has to be done, has to be done.
Nìco se musí udìlat, musí se udìlat.
We have to work out.
Musíme to vypracovat.
Even if I go to hell, I’ll have to work it out.
I kdy bych šla do pekla, musím to vypracovat.
That’s my job.
To je moje práce.
That’s what all of them and you, all put together, have to help me.
S tím Mi oni všichni spolu s vámi dohromady musíte pomoct.
Because all this anger, everything, will pass away.
Protoe tento hnìv, všechno, to pomine.
What will remain is the achievement,
Zùstane to, co je úspìch.
the achievement that we have
Úspìch, kterého jsme
accomplished by our perseverance and our patience.
dosáhli naší vytrvalostí a naší trpìlivostí.
So once we realise the achievement
Take jakmile si uvìdomíme úspìch
and the importance of the achievement,
a dùleitost úspìchu,
we do not give way to these temporary moods
nedáme šanci tìmto doèasnım náladám,
we have to be absolutely tranquil and understanding about it.
musíme v tom bıt naprosto klidní a chápající.
Also in this way we play into the hands of the negative forces,
Takto také nahráváme negativním silám,
because they want to be disturbing,
protoe ony chtìjí bıt rušivé
and we play into their hands in the anger.
a my jim hnìvem nahráváme.
So actually, when we are angry, actually
Take vlastnì kdy se hnìváme,
we are going against ourselves.
jdeme sami proti sobì.
You are playing into the hands of the negative.
Hrajete do rukou negativity.
So what’s the use of getting angry and showing temper?
Tak k èemu je hnìvat se a mít vztek?
It is addressed to these angry natural things that.
To je adresováno tìm nazlobenım pøírodním vìcem.
Alright. Now, we should start our puja
V poøádku. Teï bychom mìli zaèít naši púdu.
because I think we should start it and it will settle down then with the puja.
protoe myslím, e bychom mìli zaèít a pak se to s púdou utiší.
As it is, when I first came to England I said there is a big
Kdy jsem poprvé pøišla do Anglie, øíkala jsem, e je zde velké
curse of the Goddess on this country.
prokletí Bohynì vùèi této zemi.
Really. That time the climate was just like this.
Opravdu. Tenkrát bylo klima pøesnì takové.
And you could not even step out of your door.
A nemohli jste udìlat ani krok ze dveøí.
We were staying in Alwich, I remember.
Byli jsme v Alwich, pamatuji si,
And the car was hardly about, say, ten feet,
a auto bylo sotva okolo, øeknìme, deseti stop,
and we didn’t know how to reach the car, it was so windy.
a my jsme nevìdìli, jak se do auta dostat, tak moc vál vítr.
And we were wearing coats and everything, but everything was
A mìli jsme kabáty a všechno, ale všechno bylo
absolutely in a windy state.
naprosto ve vìtru.
And then I said that this country is really under the curse of the Goddess.
A tehdy jsem øekla, e tato zemì je opravdu Bohyní prokletá.
But the one who curses also can take back the curse, isn’t it?
Ale ten, kdo prokleje, mùe také vzít kletbu zpìt, e?
But this is Vishnumaya, always very angry. Actually she’s very, very angry person.
To je Višnumája, která je velmi rozzlobená.
When she gets angry, she tries to show her anger.
Kdy se rozzlobí, zkouší projevit svùj hnìv.
So as it is, you know, it is part and parcel of me,
Tak, jak to je - víte, je to Moje èást a souèást,
but my own part and parcel suggests –
ale Moje èást a souèást navrhuje -
like, supposing there’s something burning,
jako, napøíklad, zde nìco hoøí
and I put my foot on that.
a Já na to šlápnu.
It suggests, my foot suggests me that this is hot,
Navrhne to - Moje chodidlo mi navrhne, e to je horké,
better not put your foot. It’s like that.
radìji na to nestoupej. Tak to je.
So let us see how the puja works out today.
Take uvidíme, jak dnes zafunguje púda.
It’s a great challenge to all of us.
Je to pro nás všechny velká vızva.
Let us do it with shraddha, don’t have ashraddha,
Dìlejme to se šradhou, nemìjte ašradhu.
then it will work out, I’m sure it will work out.
Pak to bude pracovat, jsem si jistá, e se to zpracuje.
You are my better children
Jste moje lepší dìti.
May God bless you.
A vám Bùh ehná.